Guide to the Martin Wong Papers MSS.102
Fales Library and Special Collections
Martin Wong Papers
circa 1982-1999
1939-1999
Fales Library and Special Collections
Wong, Martin
MSS.102
30.5 Linear Feet in 21 manuscript boxes, 7 record cartons, 13 flat boxes, 12 box binders, and one flat file folder.
Artist Martin Wong (1946-1999) was a respected and prolific painter in New York's downtown art scene. He also cultivated both working and personal relationships with graffiti artists and enthusiasts. The Martin Wong Papers date from 1982 to 1999 and contain Wong's artwork, including sketches, drawings, and graffiti, as well as correspondence, poetry, prose, and source material that informed his artwork.
Provenance
The Martin Wong Papers were donated by the estate of Martin Wong, overseen by Mrs. Benjamin (Florence) Wong Fie and assisted by Wendy Olsoff and Peter Broda, in December 1999 and January 2000. Most of the materials in the collection were retrieved from Wong's Lower East Side apartment; additional documents were donated by Mrs. Wong Fie from her personal papers.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers.
Biographical Note
Martin Wong is known for his paintings of gritty cityscapes, including New York's Chinatown and Lower East Side, and for championing graffiti as a legitimate art form in the 1980s and 1990s. Wong was a respected and prolific painter in New York's downtown art scene in the 1980s. In addition, Wong cultivated both working and personal relationships with graffiti artists and enthusiasts.
Born Martin Victor Wong (although sometimes playfully listed himself as "Martin Genghis Wong") in Portland, OR, on July 11, 1946, Wong was raised by his Chinese-American parents in San Francisco. He graduated from George Washington High School in 1964. Wong was involved in performance art in the 1970s, but focused almost exclusively on painting after moving to New York in the early 1980s.
In addition to his painting, Wong experimented with poetry and prose, much of which he recorded on long paper scrolls. Highly anecdotal and semi-autobiographical, Wong's writing features an exuberant and fanciful stream-of-consciousness style.
Fascinated by New York's renegade graffiti artists, Wong befriended "Daze" (Chris Ellis), "Lee" (Lee Quiñones), "Laroc" and "LA2" (Angel Ortiz) among others. Wong forged a particularly strong and enduring friendship with Daze, and helped publicize his work, as well as the work of other graffiti artists, in exhibitions and through the Museum of American Graffiti. This grassroots institution was devised to showcase the vibrant panoply of contemporary graffiti art.
Wong's circle also included arts journalist Theresa Herron, Steve Hernandez, "Magic Sam," artist John Ahearn, "Lady" Joyce Ryan, Barry Blinderman, and Wendy Olsoff and Penny Pilkington of the PPOW gallery. Also significant in Wong's life were his mother, Mrs. Benjamin (Florence) Wong Fie, and his "Aunt Nora" (a.k.a. Aunt Ellie), Eleanora Tam. In artistic terms, one of Wong's most significant relationships was that shared with poet and playwright Miguel Piñero, whom Wong met in 1982. Affectionately referred to by Wong as both "Mikey" and "Mickey," Piñero was considered "Loisaida's reigning outlaw poet" (Sweet Oblivion, 35). A some-time roommate of Wong's, Piñero collaborated with Wong on such paintings as "Attorney Street Handball Court" (1982-84) and "Little Got Rained On" (1983). Piñero's text was incorporated into the paintings such that Wong's imagery serves as evocative illustration. Piñero also appears in Wong's paintings as subject - "Portrait of Piñero" (1982), "Penitentiary Fox" (1988), "La Vida" (1988) - where he is typically depicted reading or writing.
In the span of a decade, Wong achieved considerable recognition and success, with solo and group exhibitions to his credit. Wong is most closely associated with downtown galleries Semaphore, Exit Art, and PPOW, but his work has also appeared at such venues as the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the New Museum of Contemporary Art, and the New-York Historical Society. Wong died in 1999, after a protracted battle with AIDS.
Sources/Related Material:
The Clones of Bruce Lee [videorecording]: the art of Martin Wong. (New York: Pow Wow Productions, 1995) Martin Wong [videorecording]. (New York: Pow Wow Productions, c1998) Sweet Oblivion: the urban landscape of Martin Wong. (New York: Rizzoli Books, c1998)
Scope and Content Note
The Martin Wong Papers are comprised of over 100 sketches and drawings, more than 30 sketchbooks, correspondence, poetry and prose, biographical documents, source material, audio and videocassette recordings, photos, and graffiti tag-books, graffiti-related materials and parts of Wong's personal library.
Source material includes magazines, postcards, posters, memorabilia, and a vast collection of Wong's snapshots. Biographical material features Wong's curriculum vitae, copies of newspaper and magazine profiles of Wong, business cards and addresses of associates, and publicity materials related to Wong's exhibitions. Wong's poetry and prose contains a significant portion of the biographical material - much of it anecdotal in tone. The graffiti portion of the archive is comprehensive and includes sketchbooks, illustrations, text on graffiti (authored by both Wong and others), publicity material pertaining to graffiti exhibitions, and materials pertaining to the graffiti film: Wild Style. Of particular interest are the numerous examples of tagging found in both the sketchbooks and other artwork.
A zealous collector and graffiti enthusiast, Wong amassed a considerable cache of graffiti material in the 1980s. The Martin Wong Papers also document New York's downtown arts scene in the 1980s and 1990s, with particular emphasis on Wong's participation and recognition in the gallery scene.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading and chronologically depending on the nature of the series. Oversized material, while included in the number sequence of the series is separated into oversized boxes.
The collections is grouped into 9 series: Series I: Correspondence Series II: Artwork Series III: Source Material Subseries III.A: Catalogs, Graffiti, Invites, Posters Subseries III.B: Asian-Language Source Material Series IV: Biographical Series V: Video & Audiocassettes Series VI: Photography Series VII: Personal Library Series VIII: Albums Series IX: Tax Receipts
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
Fashion Moda Archive (MSS.091)
Separated Material
There is no record of materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Sketchbooks.; Artists and community -- United States; New York (N.Y.).; Manuscripts for publication.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Photographs.; Posters.; Clippings (information artifacts); Handscrolls.; Painting, American -- New York (State) -- New York.; East Village (New York, N.Y.); Drawings; Audiotapes.; Videocassettes.; Postcards.; Urban issues.; Social conditions -- Art -- United States -- 20th century.; Art and society -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Figurative art, American -- 20th century.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Poetry.; Art, Modern -- 20th century; Art, American -- New York (State) -- New York.; Correspondence.; Books.; Downtown writers.; Graffiti.; Wong, Martin; Daze; Herron, Annie; Ahearn, John, 1951-
- Series I: Correspondence, 1982-1999; 1 Linear Feet in one record carton
  Scope and Contents
  Series I: Correspondence contains a box of documents ordered alphabetically by correspondent's last name (in most cases). Where surnames or complete names were missing, first names or nicknames were used. The series contains letters, postcards, holiday and greeting cards, and memos of both a personal and business nature.
  - ABC No Rio, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Act Up/New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aegis Networking Inc, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ahearn, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alliance for Asian American Arts and Culture, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andres, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Asian American Arts Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barrett, Sam, undated (Box 1, Folder 7a)
  - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Broken Rifles of the War Resisters League, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Byrne, David/Talking Heads, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chalk & Vermilion Fine Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chinatown History Project, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Circle Fine Art Corporation, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community Prescription Services, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cutting, Jennifer McGregor, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Daze (Ellis, Chris), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drexler, Rosalyn, undated (Box 1, Folder 16a)
  - Dzine (Box 1, Folder 16b)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fire Dep't, City of NY, undated (Box 1, Folder 17a)
  - Flushing Council on Culture & the Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gabor, Lauren, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gavin, Jen, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Godzilla/Asian American Arts Network, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Groninger Museum, undated (Box 1, Folder 21a)
  - Hernandez, Steve, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Herron, Theresa (Zamodia, Theresa; Herron, Annie), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hiller, Kam Ping, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Human Resources Admin. Medical Assistance Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Islip Art Museum, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Jan, Janet (cousin), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Jim (nephew-?), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Jon Gerstad Gallery, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kim, Elaine (U.C. Berkeley), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center/Center Stage, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Magic Sam/"Sami Magic", undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - McDougal, Littell, & Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Needham, Peter, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Oberlin College, Dep't. of Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ordover, Jerald (attorney), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ortiz, Angel, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Pace Gallery, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Philippe Briet, Inc, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - P.P.O.W. (Pilkington, Penny and Olsoff, Wendy), undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Public Art Fund, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Queen's Museum, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Real Art Ways, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Repo History, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Richardson, Charles, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Rowberry, John W./"The Alternate", undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ryan, Lady Joyce, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Sebren, Sam, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Skipitares, Theodora, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Snug Harbor Cultural Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Sotheby's, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Swenters, Veerle, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Tam, Eleanora (Aunt Nora/Aunt Ellie), undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - UNICEF, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - White Columns, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Who's Who in American Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Wolfe, Brian, undated (Box 2, Folder 58a)
  - Wong, Martin, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Wong Fie, Mr. And Mrs. Benjamin (parents), undated (Box 2, Folder 60-61)
  - Various: Postcards, Holiday Cards, Notes, Letters, undated (Box 2, Folder 62-63)
- Series II: Artwork, 1982-1999; 3.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons and 4 oversize flat boxes.
  Series II: Artwork contains sketches, drawings, sketchbooks. Because of missing chronological or titular information, the files are not arranged within the sub-series.
  Arrangement
  This series is divided into two sub-series: Series II.A: Art by Wong and Series II.B: Art by Others.
  - Subseries II.A: Art by Wong, 1982-1999
    This subseries contains Wong's artwork, including sketches, drawings, and sketchbooks.
    - Sketchbook: Daze, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Sketchbook: Datamark Writing Tablet, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Sketchbook: "Delta, May 3, May 15", undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Joseph Narcisse Sketchbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Sketchbook: "Where Is He Now", undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Sketchbook: "Graffiti Hall of Fame", undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Sketchbook: Cactus, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Sketchbook: "Doug Ashford", undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Sketchbook: Adam Riech, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Sketchbook: "Greenroom", undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Sketchbook: "Chalfant", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Sketchbook: "Cityscapes", undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Sketchbook: "How many times have you been promised...", undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Sketchbook: "Bellevue/Latch", undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Mini-Sketchbook with Chinatown Sketches (unbound), undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Mini-Sketchbook with Sign Language Sketches, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Mini-Sketchbook: Street Scene in Pen, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Mini-Sketchbook: "Acrylic Red Oxide" (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Mini-Sketchbook: Orange Memo Book (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Sketchbook: Embossed Stamp Tag (Blank), undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Sketchbook: "United States Bronze Sign", undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Sketchbook: "Before: Mikey Reads a Poem", undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Sketchbook: Man with Mustache, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Sketchbook: Nude Woman, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Sketchbook: Including Sketches by Daryl Triviera, undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Sketchbook: Shapes in Pencil, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Drawing: "Magic Sam," Feb 15 1985 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Drawing: "Ana Pena", undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Drawing: "Bella," April 8 1994 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Drawing: Marie Antoinette Studies with Text, undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Drawing: Carrots with Text, undated (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Drawing: Bathroom studies, undated (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Drawing: "God Dog Holy Fool", undated (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Sketch: Man's Face, undated (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Transparency: "Yield" (in sign language), undated (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Sketch: Wong's Apartment Viewed through Window, undated (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Drawing: Chess Game, undated (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Sketch: Figure Study of Seated Man, undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Drawing: Bunny Crowd, undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Sketches: "Winner Take All/Hotcha Gotcha", undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Sketches: Project Plan Frame and Panel, undated (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Sketches: Asian Figures, undated (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Drawing: "Hip Hop", undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Sketch: "Museum of American Graffiti", undated (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Drawings: Character Heads, undated (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Drawings: Egyptian Museum Pieces (series), undated (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Drawing: Boots, undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Sketch: Sad Face, undated (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Sketch: Shopfront Grillwork, undated (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Drawing: Man Reading, undated (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Drawing: Person in Cowboy Hat, undated (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Drawing: "Free Willy", undated (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Drawing: Seated Figures, undated (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Drawing: "Semaphore", undated (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Drawing: Luggage, undated (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Drawing: Household Items, undated (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Drawings: Sign Language Series, undated (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Sketches: Chinatown series, undated (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Sketch: Interior with Open Doors, undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Drawings: Archaic Chinese Script, undated (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Sketches: Cityscapes, undated (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Drawing: Chinese garden, undated (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Sketches: Eastern Statuary Series, undated (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Sketch: Man with Gaping Mouth, undated (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Sketch: Pointing Hand with Text Fragment, undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Sketch: Man's Tattooed Back, undated (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Drawings: Studies for "My Self-Portrait", undated (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Sketches: Figure Studies, undated (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Drawing: Head of a Woman with Pink Hair, undated (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Drawing: Large Breasts, undated (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Drawing: Little Green Man with Graffiti Tags, undated (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Drawings: Animation Characters, undated (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Drawing: Man with Big Cigar, undated (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Sketch: "Martin Wong Chinatown USA", undated (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Drawing: Two Door Car, undated (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Drawing: "Rump Roast", undated (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Drawing: Female Figure, undated (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Drawing: Guitar Player, undated (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Sketch: Reclining Figure, undated (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Sketch: "Honey I'm Home!" / Severed Arm, undated (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Sketch: Seated Figure, undated (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Drawing: Diner Interior, undated (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Drawing: "Sam Performing", undated (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Sketch: "Help! I'm Over-Sexed!", undated (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Sketch: "Your Christmas Bonus", undated (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Drawings: License Plates and Car Makes, undated (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Drawing: "Mikey Writing 'Short Eyes'" [Miguel Pinero], undated (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Drawing: "Little Mikey Pinero Penitentiary Fox" [Miguel Pinero], undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Drawing: Miguel Pinero, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Drawing: Cat Cradled, 1985-01-22 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Artwork: "My Trip to America by Martin Wong", circa 1989 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Drawings: Humanoid Figures, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Drawing: "Time" front & back covers, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Art in Altered "Conduct of Ceremonies Handbook", undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Artwork on pages 18-27.
    - Artwork: "Mona Lisa" cover, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Art in Altered Book: "Bible in a Wet Towel"/"Razor in a Toothbrush;" "We had a gas station out on the Mojave", undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
      Artworks on pages 308-309; 328-329.
    - Sketches: Abstract Linear, Pen and Ink, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Sketches: Abstract LInear, Pen and Ink, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Sketches: Abstract Linear, Pencil, undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Sketches: Abstract Linear, Pencil (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Sketches: Abstract Linear, Other Media, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Drawings and Sketchbook: "The Rebels," "Kings Always Crew", 1984 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Sketches: "New Yorker" Covers Series, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Mini-sketchbooks: Animals, "Beauty without Danger," and Intersection, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Mini-sketchbooks: "Coronation of San Antonio" and Compass, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Mini-sketchbooks: "1000," Scene with Brick Wall, and "Whoever Wins Looses", undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Sketches: Musicians and Musical Instruments, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Sketches: Guitar Player on Horseback, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Sketch: "Tocci Bros. Daring Escape", undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Sketches: Skyscrapers, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Sketch: Graffiti Layout, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Sketches: Pistols Series, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Sketch: "Dental Patient", undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Sketch: Winged Figure, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Sketch: Tattoo Flash, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Sketch: "I Think I'm Going to be Sick" (1983) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Sketches: Interiors, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Drawings: Auction Items Series, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Drawings: Playing Cards, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Drawing: Sun-Dial, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Sketch: Moon and Stars, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Sketch: "Hypnos and Thanatos", undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Poem in Sign Language, undated (Box 15)
      This item is a scroll that contains a poem written by Wong and represented with drawings of American Sign Language signs for letters instead of with the Latin alphabet.
      The poem reads:
      Nutzboy claimed he never washed
      cause soap makes you soft
      even poured salt down
      my back once to prove it
      his body had the strong odor
      of cypress and axle grease
      and whenever he'd ripened
      I'd get drunk off the smell
      One look at his eyes and you just
    - Poem in Sign Language, 1983-10-27 (Box 15)
      Things we never knew time without end.
      We had a gas station out
      on the Mojave
      Weeks often passed without a car.
      I was his grease monkey
      I was not very smart
      He could do anything he wanted and I didn't care.
      Days of dust and piss
      Years passed behind the screendoor waiting
      Eternal daydream
      things we never knew time without end
    - Rainbow Brain, undated (Box 16)
      The poem, titled "Rainbow Brain," reads:
      A true story
      Once upon a time
      there was this woman named Kacey
      Who lived in a trailor
      Across from the Shop-rite
      who used to dye the hair of all the
      Department-store beauty-queens
      who used to ride on the floats in the Orange bowl parades
      she used to dye them orange and purple and green and glitter
      that but orange bowl was only once a year
      so the rest of the time she would color her own her own hair
      all kinds of colors
      first she would dye it purple
      then she'd strip it and dye it green
      and then strip it and then do a whole
      Rainbow
      Trip on it.
      This went on
      day in and day out
      year after year
      till finally one day she just died
      At the autopsy the corner
      discovered that the dye
      had seeped down through her scalp
      and dyed her brain
      Every imaginable
      color
    - Peach Fuzz, undated (Box 16)
      The poem, titled "Peach Fuzz," reads:
      Martin Wong 141 Ridge St., #9, NY 10002598–9883
      Peach fuzz
      A true story by Martin Wong
      I think it was either Michigan Boulevard in Wisconsin or maybe
      it was Wisconsin Boulevard in Michigan
      anyway it was
      America
      Somewhere
      Brian and Jabbo were driving around
      nowhere to go
      so Jabbo he pulled down his pants
      stuck a cigarette in his big hairy butt
      and put a hat on it so it looked like a gross
      Little man with a incredibly ugly face
      and no eyes then
      they drove up to the guy on the corner
      and he says "hey man you know the way to Lakeside Drive? "
      And when the guy
      he turned around
      he was so shocked
      he puked on the spot!
    - Sign Language Art: Off-set reproductions of 3 images (2 copies each), undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
      These pieces show drawings of hands making American Sign Language signs for letters of the alphabet.
    - Drawings: Sign Language (series) in Graphite Ink, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 104)